<Document>
[color=#ffd700]Welcome to Space Station 14! This is a role-playing game about a shift gone wrong on a space station, where you play as a character who at any moment can become a victim of tragic events or save the day and become a hero of the station. Use the game mechanics and work together with other players to create fascinating and unique stories in the setting of a dystopian corporate future.[/color]

If you have any questions about the rules during the game, use the admin help by pressing F1 in the game or the ‘AHelp’ button in the lobby.

[color=#ffd700]0. Don’t be an asshole.[/color]

We all play the game to have a good time, and hope for mutual understanding and adequate attitude.

[color=#ff0000]If someone enters the server only to grief, insult others or spoil the game in any other way, they will be quickly pointed to the exit, most often with a permanent ban. [/color]

Violation of server rules deprives a player of protection from the administration and can be punished by other players in-character.

[color=#ffd700]1. Griefing.[/color]

Excessive and unreasonable destruction of the station and its structures, shuttles (especially the escape shuttle) and player built structures is prohibited.

Murder without the possibility of resurrection, total isolation or other means of taking a player out of the round without a worthy reason is unacceptable.

Abuse of the authority of your position is punishable by a job ban for it and related positions.


[color=#ffd700]2. Ignoring your role.[/color]

You should not ignore the chain of command, fulfil the responsibilities of other roles or ignore your own responsibilities without valid reasoning.

Command roles are expected to have higher standards of role-playing and responsibility for orders and decisions given.

AI, Borgs, and other synthetics (with the exception of IPCs) are soulless machines, so they cannot violate the laws built into them and have stricter roleplaying requirements.

If someone clearly threatens your character and you refuse to obey, they have every right to carry out their threat.


[color=#ffd700]3. Breaking the immersion.[/color]

Players are expected to put effort into their character's in-game speech, so when communicating IC it is prohibited:
- Irreparable illiteracy.
- Brainrot - use of slang not fitting the station setting, excessive acronyms and abbreviations. Traditional role names (HOS, HOP, CMO, etc.) are allowed.
- Obvious references (‘Ryan Gosling’).
- OOC in IC (‘how to switch hands?’).
- Smiley faces, symbols and parentheses)) in speech.
- Only writing lines no longer than one word.
- Improper use of the “emotes” chat. (*he hit me*).

In-game races follow their own naming standards, according to the random generator in the character creation menu. Jokey and silly names are forbidden, as well as obvious references to real-life personalities and famous characters. For clowns and mimes, a name with lower requirements can be chosen.
The description (flavor) set in the customisation menu should only reflect the visible features of the character.
Munchkinism or ‘collecting all items for all occasions’ is acceptable until you start to look like an action hero (clown), ready to do anything to overcome any difficulties.

[color=#ffd700]4. Metagaming.[/color]

  Do not share information about the events of the current round in LOOC/OOC chats and do not use third-party means of communication to coordinate actions in the game.

  In modes with antagonists, do not prepare for possible threats in advance or raise the alarm without having decent evidence. You should also not reveal enemy equipment unknown to your character.

  Any character forgets the circumstances of their death after cloning or brain transplant.

  When taking a ghost role, you forget your past life and must follow the rules of that role.

  Unwarranted actions towards characters based on experience from past rounds (metahate/metafriending) are forbidden.

[color=#ffd700]5. Responsible antagonism.[/color]

  The task of the antagonists is to make the round more interesting and dangerous for the other players within reasonable limits.

  The objectives given to the syndicate agents are not limiting. An agent can play out any of their ideas, except for the trivial destruction of the entire station or crew.

  Team antagonists are expected to work as a team to achieve a common goal.

  Some game modes imply that you can become an antagonist during the course of the game unwillingly. This means that you automatically accept the other side's rules and must contribute to the common goal.

  If you feel that you are not meeting your goals as the game progresses or do not understand what is required of you to achieve them, please contact the administration for help via AHelp.

  [color=#ffd700]6. Interacting with antagonists.[/color]

  Regular crew members may not attempt to join antagonists without reason. Indirect assistance to antagonists is allowed, as well as assistance after appropriate wagering with a meaningful reason (bribery, intimidation, etc.).

  You should not make it the goal of your game to defeat antagonists. They are the same players as you whose goal is to make the round more interesting for everyone.

  Targeted hunting of antagonists (Validhunting) without being part of the Security is unacceptable. The only exception is if the Security itself is not present or if the antagonist is an open threat to the entire crew.

[color=#ffd700]7. Cheating.[/color]

  It is forbidden to use third-party software and game flaws to gain an advantage in gameplay.

[color=#ffd700]8. ERP.[/color]

[color=#ff0000]Erotic roleplaying, in any form, is forbidden. [/color]
</Document>
